ARAM ABDULLAH

Manchester, England M3 3GZ 07563245998 - Aram221b@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I started in early 2021 with a huge challenge! Having left a previous role of 3+ years in the telesales and telecommunications industry. Have been learning to become a full stack Developer with ZTM, which has now been completed. And on a new journey with IN4 Group. The course started with the fundamental of JavaScript, going on the cover various backend and the frontend technologies such as SQL, Postgres SQL, Express, React, HTML, and CSS to name a few.

Implementing pair programming throughout. Thoroughly enjoyed the course and now am searching for the first developer role!

WORK HISTORY

01/2020 - Current

Jr Full-Stack

Web Development - Manchester, England

- Working on Real client project with IN4 Group
- Mastering JavaScript and JS frameworks like (React / Redux / Hooks ...) and contributing to open source projects within Agile and team collaboration.
- Deploying and merging with Netlify, Heroku, and GitHub...
- Great time management and meeting deadlines and balancing out between personal development and finding projects that allow providing unique value to clients.

01/2021 - 06/2021

WordPress Designer

Growth Company - Manchester, Piccadilly

- Built design mockups and prototypes with Adobe Creative Cloud, Crello, PaintShop Pro, and Elementor.
- Standardized style guides to achieving cohesive brand identity.
- Devised design solutions to meet client brief requests.

01/2018 - 12/2019

Sales Team Member

Vodafone LTD – Manchester, wythenshawe

- Great work within sales Inbound and Outbound always go above and beyond meeting company targets and bounces.
- Effectively communicate complex technical concepts to non-technical consumers using outstanding interpersonal skills.
- Offered customers clear options of phone contracts and other offers type, quality, and quantity to best meet their needs.

SKILLS

- HTML5 / CSS
- JavaScript / TypeScript
- React / Redux/ NPM, LESS / SASS / Bootstrap
- AWS / MSSQL server / MongoDB / REST API Design
- LAMP stack
- Git / GitHub / Linux Administration / terminal
- Agile
- Most frameworks like (bootstrap/tailwind...)

EDUCATION

05/2022

Skills City Bootcamp: Software engineering

IN4 Group - Manchester

Technologies used JavaScript, ReactJS, NodeJS and other static programming languages like HTML5, CSS, SASS with hand on real client projects and meeting deadlines within Agile

02/2021

Programming: Web Development

ZTM - Manchester

• Learning the latest technologies heavily focused on JavaScript ECMA 6, ReactJS, and NodeJS included frameworks and libraries like Agile and Testing

04/2016

CS: Technologies

Aleppo University - Syria